<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Pilgrims of Hope</title>
    <description>A minimal hugo theme focus on content</description>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bmm/</link>
    
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2025, Calvin Tran</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Hugo - gohugo.io</generator>
    <docs>http://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bmm//atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Bishop Martin #1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bmm/posts/letter_1/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Bishop Martin,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are substantiated reports that you intend to direct the priests of this Diocese to no longer allow the faithful to use Communion rails for the reception of Holy Communion. You must not follow through with this directive and instead allow the faithful to use Communion rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are not suppressing an objectively wrong or sacrilegious act, such as bringing your pet to Communion or carelessly disposing a Consecrated Host that fell to the ground. Instead, you are suppressing an act of reverence before the King of Kings, something that, if anything, ought to be considered praiseworthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any cursory reading of trends in the Catholic Church show that younger generations yearn for more traditional practice and devotion. Father James Martin, SJ knows this when he said to the 2025 LCWR Assembly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As we all know, there has been a shift in many young people’s desires for the church, and it is more toward the traditional.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this past September, National Catholic Reporter published an opinion piece from “That Black Catholic Chick”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Gen Z Catholics are not running toward novelty; they&amp;rsquo;re running toward reverence. They are not demanding entertainment or watered-down theology. They are searching for transcendence, for something that pierces through the noise of modern life and brings them face-to-face with the sacred.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the priestly ordinations of 2024, you mentioned how priests should not think of priesthood as “their priesthood” or “their Church.” In a similar vein, Pope Leo XIV said in his October 26, 2025 homily:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The supreme rule in the Church is love. No one is called to dominate; all are called to serve. No one should impose his or her own ideas; we must all listen to one another. No one is excluded; we are all called to participate. No one possesses the whole truth; we must all humbly seek it and seek it together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the same not apply to you? How is banning Communion rails in parishes you visit once, maybe twice a year not the zenith of imposing your personal preference upon entire parish communities? This directive is the pinnacle of rigid, callous authoritarianism diametrically opposed to any contemporary definition of synodality. If that sounds too harsh, wouldn’t you feel that way if a brother Bishop were to instead &lt;em&gt;mandate&lt;/em&gt; the usage of Communion rails for all the parishes in a Diocese? Wouldn’t you consider that the height of clericalism? Wouldn’t you consider that an absolute rejection of subsidiarity and trust in the pastors of a Diocese? Wouldn’t the faithful who internally reject this abuse of power consider their Bishop as implicitly commanding them to “pay, pray, and obey”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Gospel of Matthew, it is written:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&amp;hellip;Jesus summoned them and said, &amp;lsquo;You know that the rulers of the Gentiles lord it over them, and the great ones make their authority over them felt. But it shall not be so among you.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The faithful who wish to use Communion rails but are told they cannot will bitterly feel your authority lorded over them for no good reason. This is why your planned directive is an abuse of power and it will inflict grave spiritual harm. Pope Francis implored priests to be “shepherds with the smell of the sheep.” Please be this kind of shepherd to us. Do not issue this directive. Allow the faithful to Commune with our Lord using Communion rails when then Holy Spirit has guided the community and the consciences of the faithful to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Calvin Tran</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bmm/posts/letter_1/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Bishop Martin #2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bmm/posts/letter_2/</link>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Who is going to save our Church? Not our bishops, not our priests and religious. It is up to you, the people. You have the minds, the eyes, and the ears to save the Church. Your mission is to see that your priests act like priests, your bishops act like bishops, and your religious act like religious.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Venerable Fulton Sheen, June 1972&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Bishop Martin,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a 34 year old sinner, husband, father of five children (one due this upcoming January), and Catholic of this Diocese for over 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I attended an Installation Mass where you gave a homily asking the congregation to trust their new pastor’s spiritual leadership and to not treat you and your office like “UPS customer service.” I find it ironic and sad you do not extend the same trust with your own priests, and God is commanding me to not just write a letter that will be treated as customer service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voice of God is clear: I will hold a public three day fast in front of the Diocesan office starting the first Monday of Advent unless you guarantee pastors and faithful the right to use Communion rails. While I personally hate the idea of being seen as an activist, God is calling me to do this and I cannot say no. The spiritual freedom for my family and the rest of the faithful, and the call to resist this abuse of power is too great to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Christ,&lt;br&gt;
Michael Russell&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Calvin Tran</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bmm/posts/letter_2/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
